Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records 5929
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Records
1958-1991
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees (NUHHCE)
Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union
5929
11 cubic feet
10 linear ft.
Records (documents), audiovisual materials.
5736572
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 23, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 6085 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project "Frederick Douglass and His Time" Posters 6089 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Posters 6084 G: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Women of Hope Poster Sets 6140: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project 6069: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Additional Files 6140 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio Recordings 6169 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 6169: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Files 6169 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 6169 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs 5929 AV: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Audio-Visual Materials 5929 MB: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Memorabilia 5929 P: Local 1199 Bread and Roses Cultural Project Photographs
Clothing workers -- New York (State); Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Collective labor agreements -- Hospitals -- New York (State); Hospitals -- Employees -- Labor unions -- New York (State); Bread and Roses Cultural Project; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees; National Union of Hospital and Nursing Home Employees. Local 1199 Drug and Hospital Union (New York, N.Y.)
5736572
- Charleston, SC. 1969. (Box 1)
  - Charleston, S.C. Editorials and Features (1) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Charleston, S.C. Editorials and Features (2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Charleston, S.C. Clippings May 16, 1969 - current (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Charleston S.C. Clippings May 16, 1969-current (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Charleston, S.C. Clippings May 15, 1969-current (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Charleston, S.C. Clippings May 15, 1969-current (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Charleston S.C. Misc. (Box 1, Folder 7)
- General. 1965; 1972. (Box 2)
  - 1199: A Study of the Cultural Arts (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - League Negotiations, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    May-June Clippings
  - Contract Negotiations, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Clippings
  - Coretta Scott King, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - The Working American Exhibit [folder 1 of 2], 1980 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Working American Exhibit [folder 2 of 2], 1980 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Charleston SC Clippings (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Charleston SC (Box 2, Folder 8)
- General Files. 1979-1991. (Box 3)
  - Industrial Hostages: Factory Closing in Ohio, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Cagan. October, 1988
  - Gallery 1199 Exhibitions, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Photos of Dr. King, Fernandez Parsons School of Design
  - Martin Luther King Exhibit, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Latino in New York Exhibit, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    January 27 - March 3, 1983.
  - Social Concern and Urban Realism in the 1930s (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Patricia Hill
  - Recipients of Complimentary Copies of Social Concern Exhibition Catalogue, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    April 7, 1983
  - Spanish War Veteran Posters, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    March 9 - April 4, 1987.
  - Gallery 1199 Exhibitions: Alejandro Stuart, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    October 31 - December 7, 1990
  - Working Women, Working Artists, Working Together, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    January 6 - March 5, 1982. Includes 9 black and white photographs
  - Museum Responses to Working Americans (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - The Working American, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - The Working American (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Gallery 1199: King Remembered, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    January 12 - February 23, 1990
  - Disarming Images (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - New Age, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    August 1985
  - Disarming Images Press Clips, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    Originals
  - Disarming Images Press Clips, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    Photocopies
  - Nuclear Times, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    August 1984
  - LA Times (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Nuclear Art Write-ups (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Disarming Images (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Disarming Images (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Disarming Images (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Disarming Images Articles (Box 3, Folder 24)
- General Files. 1980-1991. 1199 News. 1974-1976. (Box 4)
  - Mill Town Publication (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Lower East Side Print shop Flyers (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mill Town Sales "Lawrence 1912: The Bread and Roses Strike" (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Gallery 1199 Lower East Side Print Shop Show, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    3/18-4/25
  - Lawrence Day (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - 1199 News National union Edition, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - 1199 News, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - 1199 National Union Edition, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - 1199 News, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - 1199 News, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- 1199 News. 1972-1973; 1977. (Box 5)
  - 1199 News, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - 1199 News, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1199 News, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1199 News, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - 1199 News, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - 1199 News, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Voice of the Mortar and Pestle (photocopy). 1929. Union Pharmacist (photocopies). 1933-1935. Clippings. General. 1959-1962. (Box 6)
  - The Union Pharmacist Etc. (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Spanish News (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 1199 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Hospital Finances and Studies (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Union Built and Operated Hospitals (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - National Association of Social Workers (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Articles, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - N.Y. City Union Drive (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - No Date (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letters to Press (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - 1960-1963 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Forand and Health Care Battle - National + State (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - News Clippings, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Nursing Homes (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Misc. (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Misc. Press Clippings (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Clips (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Drug Inquiry and Prices (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Rochester, Chicago, etc. Union Drive (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Nurses (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Drug Workers' Materials (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Editorials, 1960 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    January to July
  - Blue Cross (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Miscellaneous Files. 1962-1985. Leon Davis interviews. 1976-1977. (Box 8)
  - Hospital Union Material (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Periodicals (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - 1199 Thesis and Articles (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Leon Davis Material (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Leon Davis Transcript (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Take Care. 1991. (Box 9)
  - Take Care (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Health Care Strike (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - 1199 Bread and Roses Festival (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Flyers and Clippings (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Hospitals (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Take Care (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Moe - Clips (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Take Care (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - For Moe (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Take Care (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Images of Labor (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Clips, Periodicals (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Hospital Files (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Hospitals (Box 9, Folder 14)
- News, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  April
- News, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  June
- News Clippings (Box 12, Folder 1)
- News, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 2)
- News, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  January
- News, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 4)
- News, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  March
- News, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  Feb
- News, 1959 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  May